<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Single-cell RNA-seq analysis with R/Bioconductor</title>
    <link>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Single-cell RNA-seq analysis with R/Bioconductor</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1. Presentation</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/01_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/01_presentation/</guid>
      <description>Jacques Serizay
Manik Garg
Dates 07-11 June 2021
Where This course will be held online in response to the coronavirus outbreak.
Overview This course will introduce biologists and bioinformaticians to the field of single-cell RNA sequencing. We will cover a range of software and analysis workflows that extend over the spectrum from the best practices in the filtering scRNAseq data
to the downstream analysis of cell clusters and temporal ordering. This course will help the attendees gain accurate insights in pre-processing, analysis and interpretation of scRNAseq data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2. Program</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/02_program/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/02_program/</guid>
      <description>Classes are from:
 2 to 8 pm Paris time. 1 to 7 pm London time. 8 am to 2 pm NY time. 5 am to 11 am SF time.  Monday – Classes from 14:00 to 20:00 (Paris time)   30-sec presentation
  Shared Google doc:
   We&amp;rsquo;re a team! Present yourself! Course notes Ideas/questions/challenges/feedbacks&amp;hellip;  Overview of the course  Lecture 1 – scRNA-Seq experimental design  General introduction: cell atlas overviews Comparison of Bulk and single cell RNA-Seq Overview of available scRNA-seq technologies (10x) and experimental protocols  Lecture 2 - Intro to Data processing: from bcl file to count matrix  scRNA-Seq processing workflow starting with choice of sequencer (NextSeq, HiSeq, MiSeq) / barcode swapping and bcl files Overview of Popular tools and algorithms Common single-cell analyses and interpretation Sequencing data: alignment and quality control Looking at cool things in alignment like where reads are, mutations, splicing Read &amp;amp; UMI counting (Kallisto alignment-free pseudocounts as well), how RSEM works (length dependence, sequencing depth, multimapping reads), CellRanger (dropest), bustools  Lab 1 – Familiarizing yourself with the course AWS instance  Logging in AWS Shell and Unix commands to navigate directories, create folders, open files Raw file formats Using RStudio Get data from 10x website, single cell portal, from GEO (fastqs, counts)  Lab 2 – Processing raw scRNA-Seq data  Data outputs from different scRNAseq technologies (10x, Smart-seq2) Quality Control reports (CellRanger, dropEst, fastqc) Mapping sequencing data with Cellranger  Tuesday – Classes from 14:00 to 20:00 (Paris time) Lecture 3 - Expression QC, normalisation and gene-level batch correction  What CellRanger does for quality filtering PBMC data Normalisation methods https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3. Contacts</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/03_contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/03_contacts/</guid>
      <description>Contacts Jacques Serizay: jacques.serizay@pasteur.fr Manik Garg: manikg@ebi.ac.uk Shared Google Drive folder: https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1AhShrHbS4bK_ta7gKqcXGLGgAEXmc9lJ?usp=sharing Don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to introduce yourself!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4. Rstudio</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/04_rstudio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/04_rstudio/</guid>
      <description>Rstudio offers a graphical interface to facilitate the interaction between a user and an underlying programming language (this is sometimes called IDE, or integrated development environment). It can be very useful when a user is not necessarily proficent with command line-based computing. However, such graphical interfaces are not always able to connect to services such as AWS.
Since most of the preliminary analysis we do is on AWS, we&amp;rsquo;d like to be able to use Rtudio directly from there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5. Prerequisites and required local config</title>
      <link>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/05_prerequisites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://js2264.github.io/scRNAseq_Physalia_2021/introduction/05_prerequisites/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisites The course is intended for those who have basic familiarity with Unix and the R scripting language.
We will also assume that you are familiar with mapping and analysing bulk RNA-seq data as well as with the commonly available computational tools.
 If a refresher is needed for Unix command line (hopefully not), please go over this tutorial and its companion cheatsheet . For a refresher in R/Bioconductor: please read the comprehensive R/Bioconductor book from Kasper D.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
